(
"ai_sub_version": "2.9.1",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch"
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 5,
"max": 5,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
しゅわーっ！
Shuwa!
ホロライブ2期生、大空スバル！
Hololive's 2nd generation, Oozora Subaru!
今日はみんな楽しんでってねー！
Everyone, make sure to have fun today!
ちょこっとやんちゃで
A little mischievous,
にこっとおどけて...
with a playful grin...
元気な キラッと スマイル アイドル
An energetic, sparkling smile idol!
毎日もっと楽しくしたい
I want to make every day even more fun!
どうよ？ go with アドベンチャー
How about that? Go with adventure!
ひらひらスカートも
Even this fluttering skirt...
ちゃんと着こなせるんだよ
I can wear it perfectly, you know!
だからもっともっと
So, more and more,
気になってもいいよ
it's okay to fall for me!
一緒に 大空に飛び立とう
Let's fly away together into the great big sky!
ひかれ！
Shine!
どんな輝きの中も 強いきらめき
Even in any kind of brightness, a strong sparkle...
君に届いているかな？
I wonder if it's reaching you?
1ミリでも伝わればいい
Even if only a millimeter gets through, that's fine!
ゴー！ チャージ！ チャレンジ！ 全力アクセル！
Go! Charge! Challenge! Full-throttle accelerator!
頑張る君へ
To you, who are doing your best,
一番乗りのスマイルを送る スバルチャンネル
sending my first-arrival smile on the Subaru Channel!
エブリデイ 悩んで みんなで
Every day, let's face our worries together!
ブルーな気持ちに ズバッと駆けつけ お助けしちゃう ヒーロー
Rushing right over to your blue feelings, a hero to save the day!
弱いハートじゃいられないから つよつよでいきましょう
Because we can't stay weak-hearted, let's go with super strength!
ハラハラ波しぶき
Slightly nervous wave splashes...
ドキドキのときめきたい
I want to feel a heart-pounding excitement!
いつでもおいでよ 一年中パラダイス
Come over anytime, a paradise all year round!
どかんと
With a bang...
曇り空 吹き飛ばそう
let's blow away the cloudy skies!
あがれ！
Rise!
サマー！ どんな暗闇の中も 眩しく照らす
Summer! Brightly shining through any darkness...
君に見つけてもらえたら
If you could find me,
それだけでも 運命なんだ
just that alone is destiny!
もっと ずっと 道は続いていく 夢に向かって
Our path continues on, further and further, towards our dreams!
一緒に来てくれるかな？ その手とって 走れ
Will you come along with me? Take my hand and run!
連れていくよ みんなで
I'll take you there, everyone together!
かがやく 恥ずかしいけれど
Shining, though it's a bit embarrassing,
伝えたい思い
the feelings I want to convey...
今なら言える
now I can say them!
君のエールが力になるよ
Your cheers give me strength!
いつも元気を分けてくれて
Always sharing your energy with me,
頑張っていけるんだ 笑って過ごせるんだ
I can keep doing my best, and spend my days smiling!
本当に
Truly,
ありがとうの気持ちを
this feeling of gratitude,
歌えたら
if I can sing it...
シャイン！
Shine!
どんな輝きの中も
Even in any kind of brightness,
強いきらめき
a strong sparkle...
君に届いているかな？
I wonder if it's reaching you?
1ミリでも伝わればいい
Even if only a millimeter gets through, that's fine!
もっと ずっと 道は続いていく 夢に向かって
Our path continues on, further and further, towards our dreams!
一緒に来てくれるかな？ その手とって 走れ
Will you come along with me? Take my hand and run!
連れていくよ みんなで
I'll take you there, everyone together!
君と駆ける スバル
Running with you, Subaru!
大空スバル 7周年ライブ！始まる、始まるー！
Oozora Subaru's 7th Anniversary Live! It's starting, it's starting!
いつも迷惑ばかりかけるけど
I always end up causing trouble for you,
いつも散々困らせちゃうけど
I always end up making things so difficult,
それでも隣にいてくれる
but still, you stay by my side,
君のそばにずっと
always right here with you.
曖昧な言葉じゃ
With vague words,
真面目な君には伝わらない
I can't get through to serious you,
頑丈なそのハートを 覗いてみたい
I want to peek inside your strong heart,
融かしてみたい
I want to melt it.
そんな時こんな魔法はどうかな？
How about this kind of magic for times like this?
何が出るかな？
What will come out?
やっちゃえ！
Let's do it!
せーの！
Ready, set!
try try try
あやふやだって
Even if it's uncertain,
いいの！いいの！
it's okay! It's okay!
which one to pick
watch me do magic
あらら想像以上の展開
oh, this is turning out better than I imagined,
もう止められないのよ
I can't stop now.
ごめんなさい
Sorry,
溢れる想いで空回り
my overflowing feelings are spinning out of control,
振りかけるhappyなイメージ
sprinkling happy images around,
で振り回すfancyなマジック
and casting fancy magic everywhere!
また君に
To you again...
...けどほら
...but look!
こんなDay by dayがいい
I like this kind of Day by day
あの日から Falling in love with you
Since that day, Falling in love with you
変わらないからずっと Only you
Because it won't change, always Only you
だからほら うだうだしてる場合じゃないの
So look, this is no time to be dilly-dallying!
掴めハッピーエンディング
Grab that happy ending!
いつまでも 隣で笑っていたいのよ
I want to keep laughing by your side forever
いつも仲間はずれで とぼとぼの毎日
Always left out, plodding through each day,
そんな私の前に 現れた君は
When you appeared before me,
同じ寂しさを 抱えている
Carrying the same loneliness as me,
とても とても 優しい人
You are a very, very kind person.
今も心配事は多いけど
Even though there are still many worries,
もう私も君も 一人じゃない
Neither you nor I are alone anymore.
騒がしくて愛おしいこの日々が ずっと続きますように
I hope these noisy, precious days will continue forever
3, 2, 1
飛ばせ happyなイメージ
Send out a happy image!
とびきりの fancyなマジック
With an extraordinary, fancy magic!
また君に くどくど言われそうだけど
I bet you'll nag at me again, but...
そんな Day by day がいい
I like this kind of Day by day
あの日から Falling in love with you
Since that day, Falling in love with you
気づいて欲しいの Loving you
I want you to notice, Loving you
だからここ うだうだしてる場合じゃないの
So look, this is no time to be dilly-dallying!
次はどんなプランニング
What's the next plan?
そしてまた 今日もハプニング
And there's another happening today
明日はどんな
What kind of...
おかしなことが起こるかな
strange things will happen tomorrow?
ずっと隣で見ててね
Watch over me by my side forever
happyなイメージ
A happy image!
fancyなマジック
Fancy magic!
happyなイメージ
A happy image!
fancyなマジック
Fancy magic!
ハイタッチ☆メモリー (LIVE High-Touch☆Summer ver.)
[Song: High-Touch☆Memory (LIVE High-Touch☆Summer ver.)]
いっせーのでキミとだけ！
On three, let's do it, just you and me!
もう少し眠りたいけど
I want to sleep a little more, but...
もったいないよ 今日はサンデー
That's such a waste, today is Sunday!
楽しいこと やりたいこと wake up! 始めようよ
Fun things, things I want to do, wake up! Let's get started!
めくりめく季節 キミと 次のステージへ
In this dazzling season with you, onto the next stage!
声を合わせて 扉開けて 駆けだせ 迷わずに
Raise our voices, open the door, and run out without hesitation!
転んでも カッコ悪くても いいじゃない
Even if we fall or look uncool, isn't it fine?
stand up! イメージもっと 重ねていく その先で
Stand up! Let's build up our images even more, beyond that...
いっせーのでキミとだけ
On three, just you and me,
ハイタッチ 手叩いて
high-five, clapping hands!
奏でる メロディーを
With the melody we play...
合図に走りだせ
as our cue, let's start running!
キミとなら 怖くない
With you, I'm not afraid.
ハイタッチ 手と手叩いて
High-five, hand against hand!
重ねる そのメモリーは
These memories we pile up...
明日への エネルギー
are our energy for tomorrow!
さぁいこうよ もっと先へ
Come on, let's go even further!
キミとなら Happy Lucky Life!
With you, it's a Happy Lucky Life!
あの日見た夢の続き 追いつくその日まで
The continuation of the dream we saw that day, until the day we catch up...
涙なんて 振り切るくらい もっと speed up!
Shake off those tears, speed up even more!
どんな未来になったとしても 後悔しないよ
No matter what kind of future lies ahead, I won't regret a thing!
自分自身 選んだ道 踏み出せ 迷わずに
Step forward on the path you chose yourself, without hesitation!
落ち込んで 進めなくなったときは
When you're feeling down and can't move forward,
wake up! 思い返す 夢見た頃の記憶を
Wake up! Remember the memories of when we dreamed...
手と手で奏でる(叶える) 響きを(きらめく夢を) キミとだけ
Let's play and fulfill it hand-in-hand, a resounding sparkling dream, only with you!
ハイタッチ その度に
High-five, and each time we do...
繋がっていく心
our hearts connect even more
一人じゃないことを 気づかせてくれたよね...
You made me realize that I am not alone, didn't you?
ハイタッチ 手と手叩いて
High-five, hand against hand!
奏でるそのメロディーが
The melody we play...
世界に届くまで
until it reaches the entire world...
この夢は続いていく
this dream will go on!
キミとなら Happy Lucky Live!
With you, it's a Happy Lucky Live!
くじけて歩けない日は
On days you're too discouraged to walk,
おんぶしてあげるキミを
I'll carry you on my back!
ほら見て そっちのほうが
Look over there, that way...
強気自慢 踏み込める
we can take a step forward with pride!
巡り巡る日々を たどり夢みたステージへ
Through the passing days, to the stage I've dreamed of...
届きそうな希望を見つめて
Staring at the hope that seems within reach.
起こそうよ 君とだけ
Let's make it happen, only with you!
手と手を鳴らすたび
Every time our hands clap together,
小さなビッグバン
a tiny big bang occurs.
無限のその力を
Receive that infinite power,
受けて進め！
and move forward!
ハイタッチ 手たたいて
High-touch, clap your hands!
奏でるメロディーを
Play the melody...
合図に走り出せ Go!
And start running at the signal! Go!
君となら怖くない
With you, I'm not afraid.
ハイタッチ 手と手たたいて
High-touch, clap hand-to-hand!
重なるそのメモリーは
Those overlapping memories...
明日へのエネルギー
Are the energy for tomorrow!
さあ行こうよ もっと先へ
Come on, let's go further ahead!
君となら Happy Lucky Life!
With you, it's a Happy Lucky Life!
というわけで、みなさん！
And with that, everyone!
大空スバル7周年記念ライブ「ラブミ！」にお越しくださり
Thank you so much for coming to Oozora Subaru's 7th Anniversary Live, "LOVE ME!"
ありがとうございます！イェーイ！
Thank you so much! Yay!
ちわーす！このライブにきて、大空スバール！よろしくお願いしまーす！
Chiwass! Welcome to this live show, I'm Oozora Suba—ru! Nice to meet you!
ということで、ついに「ラブミ！」が始まる、始まる！
So, "LOVE ME!" is finally starting! It's starting!
今日のですね、配信のハッシュタグは右上のこちらになりますので、ぜひよろしくお願いします！
Today's streaming hashtag is this one in the top right, so please use it!
いっぱいね、#大空スバル7周年LIVE をつけて、たくさん呟いてください。スバルもチェックしたいと思います！
Please tweet a lot using the hashtag "Oozora Subaru 7th Anniversary Live"! Subaru will check them out too!
そしてみなさん、気づきましたか？なんと、
And everyone, did you notice? Amazingly...
今までも可愛かったんですけど、
I was cute before, but...
でも、より可愛くしていただきました！ニュースバルです！よろしくお願いします！
They made me even cuter! This is New Subaru! Nice to meet you!
どうですか？可愛い？
How is it? Am I cute?
可愛い？！あははは！
Cute?! Ahahaha!
ぜひですね、たくさんスクショ撮ってね、
Please take lots of screenshots,
えー、呟いてください。ポストか！ポストしてください！
um, tweet them—I mean, post them! Please post them!
そしてですね、スバルはですね、通常のね、スバルもね、見てほしいので、ちょっと着替えてきていいですか？着替えてきます！
And also, I want you to see the usual Subaru too, so can I go change for a bit? I'll go change!
じゃあ、行ってきます！
Alright, I'll be right back!
わー！
Wah!
うわー！
Uwah!
わー！
Wah!
通常衣装の、ニュースバル！
New Subaru in her default costume!
そしてなんと、帽子がない！
And amazingly, there's no hat!
ついに取れるようになった！やったー！
I can finally take it off! Yay!
ついに取れるようになりました！
It can finally be taken off now!
どうですか？
How is it?
可愛いですか？
Is it cute?
とてもね、えー、より可愛く、作っていただきました。髪の毛もサラサラ！
They made me, like, even cuter. My hair is so silky-smooth too!
もう本当にね、ありがとうございます！そして、
Really, thank you so much! And...
可愛いといえば、なんと！
speaking of cute, check this out!
こちらのステージ！
This stage!
とてもね、可愛いです。スバルあの、すごくゲームが好きなので、
It's so cute. Since I love games so much,
このピクセルっぽい感じでね、今年はね、作っていただきました。
they made it with this pixel-art style for this year.
イェーイ！スバルドダックもいる！
Yay! Subarudo Duck is here too!
そして、なんといってもこの、
And above all,
ピクセルスバ友も！
pixel-art Subatomo too!
めっちゃ可愛いです！もう、これが一番見せたかったと言っても過言ではない！
They're so cute! It's no exaggeration to say this is what I wanted to show you most!
ということでですね、こんな素敵なステージで、させていただいて、とても嬉し…
So, performing on such a wonderful stage makes me so hap...
あーーーー！
Ahhhh!
なんと、しれっと着替えてきました！
Oh my, I secretly changed back!
こんにちは！
Hello!
やっぱね、アイドル衣装ね、でね、やっていきたいと思います。
After all, I want to do this in my idol outfit.
ぜひ、アイドル衣装スバルもですね、
So please take lots of screenshots of Subaru
いっぱいスクショ撮って、
in her idol outfit,
ポスト！してください！よろしくお願いします！
and post them! Thank you so much!
はい、ということで、ここまではなんと、
Alright, so up until now,
ぷりあです、ウォチミ、ハイタッチメモリーの3曲をお届けしたんですけど、
we brought you three songs: Pleiades, Watch Me, and High-Touch☆Memory,
全てですね、スバルにとって思い出深い楽曲で、
and all of them are songs that are deeply memorable to me.
特に、ぷりあです！
Especially Pleiades!
絶対このニュースバルになったら、もう一番にね、みんなにね、披露したいなと思っていたので、
I've always wanted to perform this first once I got this New Subaru form,
夢叶いしものです！めっちゃ嬉しい、ありがとうございます！
so this is a dream come true! I'm so happy, thank you so much!
はい、ということで、
Alright, and so,
もうね、ここからはですね、なんと、
from here on out,
何が起こるかわからない！
nobody knows what's going to happen!
ゲストが、出てくるかもしれないし、
A guest might show up,
出てこないかもしれない。
or maybe not.
もう何が起こるかわからない！
Nobody knows what will happen!
ということで、えー、そんなライブ、お楽しみに！
So, please look forward to this live show!
この後も、もうどんどん盛り上がって楽しんでいくぞ！
From here on, let's keep getting more and more hyped and have fun!
始まる！始まる！
It's starting! It's starting!
私の全力受け止めて！
Accept my full power!
めにしゅきラッシュっしゅ！
An "eye-love-you" rush!
...めにめに oh yeah
...menimeni, oh yeah!
きゅんきゅん！ だがっちらっしゅ！ しゅきしゅき しゅきしゅき しゅき！
Kyun-kyun! Dagachira-rush! Love you, love you, love you!
きゅんきゅん！ だがっちら めにめに！ oh yeah
Kyun-kyun! Dagachira, menimeni! Oh yeah!
ギュンギュンギュントクンとー？
Gyun-gyun-gyun, with a throb...?
とんくっとん？ てんくてんく
Ton-ku-ton? Ten-ku-ten-ku!
たとえば タイムループなんかしちゃったって 運命で選んじゃうのは キミ
Even if I were to end up in a time loop, the one I'd choose by destiny is you.
(いぇいいぇいいぇい) わたしと一体全体 いやぜったい！
(Yeah, yeah, yeah!) With me, absolutely, no, definitely!
シンデレラフィットなのは そう キミ
The one who is a Cinderella fit is indeed you.
(おっおーおー) わたしが 何度も負けて落ち込んだって
(Oh-oh-oh) Even if I lose and get depressed over and over again...
めげずに特訓付き合っちゃって
You stick with me through training without getting discouraged,
モチベあげるだけブチ上げちゃって
and you boost my motivation to the absolute max!
なになに なんななんななんななー？
What's this? What, what, what, what is it?
ステップアップめっちゃしちゃって 勝って一緒に喜びあって
Stepping up so much, and rejoicing together when we win...
(ふー) 感謝してもしてもたりないんじゃー！
(Fuu!) I can't thank you enough!
カタチだけなんてナンセンス
Just having a shape is nonsense.
カタチないものがいいんです
The shapeless things are what truly matter.
えーっとね それはなんといいますか...
Let's see, how should I put this...
わぁ！ まってまって！ 今ここで伝えたいんです！
Whoa! Wait, wait! I want to tell you right here, right now!
つきなみだけど届けたい想い
It's cliché, but here's the feeling I want to deliver...
「こんなに大きくなりました♡」
"Look how much I've grown!♡"
だから 超many-manyめにめの約束 どどっとぷりーず♡
So, a ton of promises to your eyes, please!♡
もりもり many-many に返すから
I'll return them to you in heaps and heaps,
いつだって しゅきしゅきしゅきしゅきしゅぷりーむなお願いきいて
so please listen to my supreme, loving request anytime.
わたし あいたーい♡
I want to see you!♡
平熱で many-many きゅーぎゅぎゅっとエールをぷりーず♡
With normal temperature, send me tons of tight support, please!♡
ぜったいぜったい倍で返すから
I will definitely, absolutely return it to you twofold!
手渡しじゃ何年かかるかな
I wonder how many years it would take to hand it to you directly.
へびーすぎじゃない！？ でもいいんじゃない！？ Gimmie！ いつも愛をアリガトウ
Isn't that a bit too heavy!? But isn't it fine!? Gimme! Thank you always for your love.
甘いだけじゃダメだけどね
Being sweet alone isn't enough, but...
今日くらいは許してよ
at least forgive me for today.
大事な話だからもうちょっと
Since this is an important talk, just a little more...
気合いだけで言えるかな//Phew
Can I say it with just my fighting spirit?
誠心誠意を聞いてくれますか？
Will you listen to my utmost sincerity?
だから 超many-manyめにめの約束 どどっとぷりーず♡
So, a ton of promises to your eyes, please!♡
もりもり many-many に返すから
I'll return them to you in heaps and heaps,
いつだって しゅきしゅきしゅきしゅきしゅぷりーむなお願いきいて
so please listen to my supreme, loving request anytime.
わたし あいたーい♡
I want to see you!♡
デイバイデイ many-many きゅーぎゅぎゅっとエールをぷりーず
Day by day, send me tons of tight support, please!
ぜったいぜったい倍で返すから
I will definitely, absolutely return it to you twofold!
手渡しで何年かかっても
Even if it takes years to hand it to you directly...
伝えたいじゃない！ 届けたいじゃない！ Gimmie！ いつも愛をアリガトウ
I want to convey it! I want to deliver it! Gimme! Thank you always for your love.
きゅっきゅん！
Kyukkyun!
きゅっきゅん！ らたっちゅら めにめに Oh yeah!
Kyukkyun! Ratatchura menimeni, oh yeah!
ギュンギュンギュントクンとー？
Gyun-gyun-gyun, with a throb...?
ギュンギュンギュン！
Gyun-gyun-gyun!
ずっとずっとよろしくね
Please stay with me forever and ever.
ゆらゆらり はらはらり
Swaying gently, fluttering down,
彩りどり 乱れ咲き
in a riot of colors, blooming in profusion.
花の街 想い出す この空から
I remember the city of flowers from this sky.
百花繚乱 (百花繚乱)
A profusion of flowers blooming in full glory.
ひょんな出来事から やってきたこの場所は
This place where I arrived by a sudden turn of events
遥か遠くに在った 煌びやかな舞台
was a glittering stage located far, far away.
はっとするほど鮮やかな色彩が あるんだと知ったあなた
You, who realized that such breath-takingly vivid colors exist...
の無理難題に答えてく どんな旅に
I will answer your unreasonable demands on whatever journey we take.
あっと言わせるようなエキサイトな答え合わせで
With an exciting verification that will leave you amazed,
たどり着いたその先に 新しい景色が待っているんだ...
beyond where we arrived, a new scenery is waiting.
摩訶不思議なミステリー
A mysterious, profound enigma,
次から次に起こるたび
every time they occur one after another,
巧妙なからくりも暴いてみせましょう
I shall expose even the most clever tricks.
どんな難題でも 種や仕掛けはあるんだ
No matter how difficult the problem, there's always a trick to it.
不可逆は気にしない 必ずや導きだすから
I don't care about irreversibility, because I will surely guide us to the answer.
あぁ この場所で触れた 人の悲しみや喜びがある
Ah, there are people's sorrows and joys that I felt in this place.
その一つ一つが 心を震わせる...
Each and every one of them makes my heart tremble.
はっとしちゃうほど鮮やかな色彩が ここにあるんだ
Such breath-takingly vivid colors are right here.
あなたの無理難題に答えてく 毎日に
Answering your unreasonable demands day by day,
あっと言わせるようなエキサイトな答え合わせで
with an exciting verification that will leave you amazed...
たどり着いた その先に
At the end of the road I reached,
新しい私が待っているんだ
a new me is waiting.
あの頃は想像してない
Back then, I couldn't have imagined
未来が咲き始めている
that this future would start blooming.
こんな日々も悪くはないかな
I guess days like these aren't so bad after all.
ゆらゆらに ひらひらに
Swaying gently, fluttering lightly,
離れては 寄り添って
drifting apart, then drawing close.
そよぐ風に身を任せ
Entrusting myself to the gentle breeze,
夕闇に舞う
dancing in the dusk.
[曲名: KONNANじゃないっ！]
[Song: KONNAN janai!]
あの夢も アコガレも
Both that dream and that aspiration
落書きのまま ボヤけて
remain like scribbles, blurring
消える寸前
right before they fade away.
「コレガイイノ?」
"Is this what I want?"
「コレデイイノ?」
"Is this really okay?"
ふてくされてる鏡に
To the sulking mirror,
何度も問いかけた
I asked again and again.
泣きたい日も
Even on days I want to cry,
くじけそうな日も
or when I feel like giving up,
乗り越えよう
let's overcome them.
希望を浴びなきゃ
Unless we bathe in hope,
夢というツボミは
the bud known as a dream
開かないから
won't bloom!
Are you ready, GO!
走り出そう!
Let's start running!
取り急ぎ さぁ スタート!
No time to waste, let's start!
うつむかない!
Don't look down!
ふりむかない!
Don't look back!
明日は絶対 もっとShiny!
Tomorrow will definitely be even shinier!
ジブン次第!
It's up to me!
掴め未来!
Seize the future!
今すぐ スタートボタン
Right now, press the start button
押してみよう
and let's see.
私は
I am sure
こんなんじゃないはず!
I'm not meant to be like this!
あきらめも
Giving up,
言い訳も
and excuses, too—
取りまとめ リスタート!
pack them all up and restart!
「たられば」に
To rely on
すがるには
"what ifs" and "if onlys,"
まだまだ 若すぎじゃない?
aren't we still way too young?
七転び
Fall down seven times,
八起きで GO!
stand up eight, let's GO!
何度も リセットボタン
Hit the reset button as many times as it takes.
どんな夢も
No matter what dream,
きっと
surely
困難じゃないはず
it shouldn't be too hard.
信じてみよう
Let's believe in it.
私は
I am sure
こんなんじゃないはず!
I'm not meant to be like this!
3, 2, 1, GO!
こんなんじゃない!
I'm not meant to be like this!
[曲名: Great Days]
[Song: Great Days]
Shining justice 芽生えて
Shining justice, now budding inside,
Brand new bed town 交差する息吹
Brand new bed town, intersecting breaths.
岬から潮風
A salty breeze blows from the cape,
トンネル抜け鉄塔へ
heading through the tunnel toward the steel tower.
引かれ合い小道に迷い込む
Attracted to each other, getting lost on a path.
ココロに
Into my heart,
溶け込む影
a shadow melts away,
照らす黄金の "Spirits"
illuminating the golden "Spirits."
それは守り抜く光
That is the light we'll protect to the end.
Let the voice of love take you higher
集まるチカラで時さえ越えて
With our gathered strength, we will even transcend time.
1999 Bizarre Summer
...る勇気で生きる町
...in this town where our courage lives on
Breakdown, breakdown
Song of praises 響かせ
Ringing with a song of praises
Brand new up town すれ違う景色
A brand new uptown, with passing scenery
雲の切れ間に射す 光がほら降り注ぎ
Look, the light shining through the clouds pours down
イニシエの小道へ誘い込む
Inviting us onto the ancient pathway
煌めき...
A glittering...
...導く町
...guiding town
たぎる黄金の Spirits
A surging golden spirit
それは果てしない絆
That is an endless bond
Let the joy of love give you an answer
別れの時さえ砕けぬ意思で
With a will that won't break, even at the time of parting
1999 Bizarre Summer
自分乗り越え掴み取れ未来
Overcome yourself and seize the future
Breakdown, breakdown! Breakdown, breakdown!
Let the voice of love take you higher
集まるチカラで時さえ越えて
With our gathered strength, we will even cross through time
Let the joy of love give you an answer
別れの時さえ砕けぬ意思で
With a will that won't break, even at the time of parting
1999 Bizarre Summer
交わす勇気が生む讃歌 Great Days
The courage we share will create a hymn: Great Days
Breakdown, breakdown
というわけで、Great Daysをお届けしましたー！
And with that, we performed "Great Days"!
みんな楽しんでくれましたか？
Did everyone enjoy it?
ここまではですね、まず『ユメヲカケル！』。
Up until now, first we had "Yumewokakeru!".
この曲はですね、スバルもうめっちゃね、もともと大好きで絶対にやろうって決めてたんですけど、
Subaru loves this song so much, I had absolutely decided to do it from the start.
その結果、見事にウマ娘のアプリめっちゃやるようになりました！ありがとうございます！
As a result, I've ended up playing the Umamusume app a ton! Thank you!
そんな大好きな曲をみんなとできて、とっても楽しかったです！ありがとうございます！
I was so happy to do my favorite song with everyone, it was so much fun! Thank you!
そして続いて、百花繚乱でかっこよく踊れました！どうでしたか？
And next, we did a cool dance to "Hyakka Ryouran"! How was it?
このひらひらりが結構難しくて、頑張ったんですけど見てくれましたか？
These fluttering ribbons were quite difficult, but did you see them?
でもすごく踊って楽しかったです！
But it was so much fun to dance to!
そして、『こんなんじゃない！』。夢叶えし者になった時点で絶対にやろうって思ってたんですけど、
And then, "Konna n Janai!". I wanted to do this from the moment I became a "dream-fulfiller"...
ノエちゃんとルイに絶対にペンライトを振ってほしいと思って、
I absolutely wanted Noel-chan and Lui to wave their penlights,
呼ばせていただきました！楽しんでもらえたらとっても嬉しいです。
so I invited them! I hope you all enjoyed it.
そして『Great Days』はですね、ジョジョ4部の曲なんですけど、
And "Great Days" is a song from JoJo Part 4, which Subaru absolutely loves...
もう絶対これでバトンをするんだと、こうやってグルグル回してね、
and I was determined to twirl a baton to this, round and round like this,
今年も飛ばさせていただいたんですけど、
and I got to toss it again this year!
スバルの魂と書いてプライドと読む、魂のバトンを見ていただけましたか？
Did you see my baton of soul—written as "soul" but read as "pride"?
もうすごかったんだから、本当に！
It was seriously, seriously amazing!
というわけで、そんなスバルのこだわりと思いがいっぱい詰まったパートでした！
So, this part was packed with Subaru's obsession and strong feelings!
そしてなんと、ここからは嬉しいお知らせとなっております！
And now, we have some exciting news!
なんと！大空スバル活動5周年記念ライブのグッズ販売告知！
We have an announcement for Oozora Subaru's 5th Anniversary Live merchandise!
こちらをご覧くださーい！
Please take a look at this!
グッズは4種類あります！ということで、さっそく見ていきましょう！
There are four kinds of merch! So let's take a look right away!
イラストはしぐれうい先生に描いていただきました！母ちゃんありがとう！
The illustrations were drawn by Shigure Ui-sensei! Thanks, Mom!
イラストテーマは王道アイドルスバルです！
The illustration theme is "Classic Idol Subaru"!
それでは詳細を見ていきましょう！まずは、こちら！
Let's look at the details! First up is this!
スバルがファンサ！ラバーマット
Subaru's Fan Service! Rubber Mat
はーい！こちらの商品はですね、王道アイドルのスバルが描いてあるラバーマットになります。
Okay! This product here is a rubber mat featuring the classic idol version of Subaru.
以前ラバーマットを出したのは、えっと、4年前なので、
The last time I released a rubber mat was... let's see, four years ago, so...
当時買えなかった人でもね、前のご使ってて「もうボロボロになっちゃったよ」っていう人も
even for people who couldn't buy it back then, or those who have been using the old one and it's worn out...
ぜひ、新しくチェックしてみてください！
please make sure to check out this new one!
そして続いてはこちら！
And next up is this!
スバルがファンサ！カードスリーブ！
Subaru's Fan Service Card Sleeve!
こちらはですね、ラバーマットに合わせてカードスリーブも出してみました！
For this, we've released a card sleeve to go along with the rubber mat!
ラバーマットと合わせて使えば、スバルに応援されているような気持ちになれるかも、
If you use it with the rubber mat, you might feel like Subaru is cheering you on...
ということで、ぜひこちらも要チェックですよ！
So be sure to check this out as well!
そして、続いてこちら！
And next up is this!
マスコット大集合カードケース！イェーイ！
Mascot Gathering Card Case! Yay!
カードスリーブときたらね、やっぱりケースも必要でしょ！ということで、
If you have card sleeves, of course you need a case too! So...
もうスバルのね、スバルドダックから、なんと、おたうさ、あ、わたうさぎまで！そしてスバドモも！というようなね、
we have Subarudo Duck, and even Watausagi! And Subadomo too!
たくさんみんなが集まった、えー、カードケースを作ってみました！
We made a card case where everyone is gathered together!
側面はですね、カードを見せつけられる窓がついているので、
On the side, there's a window to show off your cards...
今回のカードスリーブをバシュッとさして見せるもよし、
so you can slide in this card sleeve to show it off...
そのね、切り札を見せつけるもよし、ということで、
or show off your trump card!
ぜひこちらもチェックしてみてください！
Be sure to check this out too!
そして最後はこちら！
And finally, this!
ぬいぐるみキーホルダー 動物パジャマ衣装ver.！
Plush Keyholder: Animal Pajama Outfit ver.!
こちらはですね、なんかスバル自身のぬいぐるみって、あまり出していないか、あ、もう！みたいなことを思ったので、
For this, since we haven't released many plushies of Subaru herself, I thought...
ちょっとね、アイドル衣装と対になるイメージの、お茶目な動物パジャマ衣装で作ってみました！
I'd make one with a playful animal pajama outfit to pair with the idol outfit!
ぜひね、この可愛スバルも、いろんなところに連れ回してみてください！
So please take this cute Subaru with you wherever you go!
そしてなんと、フルセット購入特典もあります！それではこちら、ドン！
And guess what, there's also a full set purchase bonus! Here it is, bam!
ステッカーがなんとね、今回ついております。とっても可愛いです。
A sticker is included this time! It's so cute.
スバルずっと前から、ステッカー出してみたいなってずっと思ってたので、
Subaru has wanted to make a sticker for a really long time...
今回ですね、夢が叶って嬉しいです。ぜひみんなのね、お気に入りの場所にペタッと貼ってみてください！
so I'm so happy my dream came true! Please paste it in your favorite spots!
そしてでは、改めてフルセットはこちらとなります！ドン！
And now, let's look at the full set once more! Bam!
やっぱりね、買うならね、シールもついてお得なフルセットの方がいいかも、
If you're buying, the full set with the sticker is definitely a better deal!
ということで、ぜひね、チェックしてみてください！
So please check it out!
以上、大空スバル7周年記念ライブのグッズ情報でした！
That's all for Oozora Subaru's 7th Anniversary Live merchandise info!
どれもですね、素敵なグッズに仕上がっておりますので、
Every single item turned out wonderfully...
ぜひですね、要チェックだ！
...so please be sure to check them out!
絶対に、絶対にチェックしてくださいね。よろしくお願いします！
Please, please check them out. Thank you so much!
はい！そしてですね、なんとこの衣装での、ニュースバル、ちょっとね、
Yes! And also, Subaru in this new outfit...
可愛いのでとても、ぜひスクリーンショット撮っていただきたいです！わーい！
is very cute, so please take some screenshots! Yay!
あ、そうか、後ろ向いたら撮れない。あはは！
Ah, that's right, you can't take one if I turn around. Haha!
どうぞ！
Go ahead!
可愛いですか？
Is it cute?
スバルのこのね、衣装のね、好きポイントはですね、この後ろの、
My favorite point about this outfit is this back part...
とても可愛い、とても可愛いリボンがですね、
where there's a very, very cute ribbon!
可愛い！
So cute!
どうですか？
How is it?
わー！可愛い！
Wow! So cute!
え、マジで語彙力ないな、今日。
Seriously, I have zero vocabulary today.
でもホントに可愛いので、ぜひみんな、いっぱいパシャッとしてください！よろしくお願いします！
But it really is cute, so please take lots of pictures! Thank you!
そしてですね、こんなに楽しいライブも、
And now, this incredibly fun live show...
もう、なんと、終盤！あー！
is already reaching its end! Ah!
それでお迎え、もうラストに向けてですね、
So, heading into the final part...
バッと駆け抜けていきたいと思いますので、ぜひみんなもね、
I want to run through it in one burst, so please...
最後まで楽しんでいただけると、すごく嬉しいです！はい！
enjoy yourselves right until the very end. I'd be so happy! Yes!
ということで、それじゃあもう、
With that said...
ラストだよ！
it's the last song!
始めちゃっていいわけ？始めちゃうよ！
Is it okay if I start? Here we go!
ということで、それではですね、
All right then, here we go!
はぁ...よし、始めたいと思います。
Phew... Alright, let's begin.
おいしょ、おいしょ。じゃあポーズとって。
Alright, let's pose.
はい！それでは聞いてください。
Yes! Please listen to...
ray
ray / 作詞・作曲：藤原基央
[Song: ray / Lyrics & Composition: Motoo Fujiwara]
寂しくなんか無かったよ
I wasn't lonely at all
ちゃんと寂しくなれたから
Because I was able to feel properly lonely
いつまでどこまでなんて
Until when, to where, and all that
正常か異常かなんて
Whether it's normal or abnormal
考える暇も無い程
To the point where I don't even have time to think
歩くのは大変だ
Walking is so tough
楽しい方がずっといいよ
It's much better to have fun
ごまかして笑っていくよ
I'll laugh it off and keep going
大丈夫だ あの痛みは
It's okay, that pain...
忘れたって消えやしない
...won't disappear even if I forget it
理想で創った道を
The path I built of ideals
現実が塗り替えていくよ
Reality is painting over
思い出はその軌跡の上で
Memories on those tracks...
輝きになって残っている
...remain as a brilliant glow
お別れしたのは何で
Why did we part...
何のためだったんだろうな
...and what was it all for?
悲しい光が僕の影を
The sad light casts my shadow...
前に長く伸ばしている
...long in front of me
時々熱が出るよ
Sometimes I get a fever
時間がある時眠るよ
I sleep when I have time
夢だと解るその中で
In a dream where I know it's a dream
君と会ってからまた行こう
I'll meet you, then set off again
晴天とはほど遠い
Far from a clear blue sky
終わらない暗闇にも
In this endless darkness
星を思い浮かべたなら
If I just picture the stars
すぐ銀河の中だ
I'm already inside the galaxy
あまり泣かなくなっても
Even if I don't cry much anymore
靴を新しくしても
Or if I get brand-new shoes
大丈夫だ あの痛みは
It's okay, that pain...
忘れたって消えやしない
...won't disappear even if I forget it
伝えたかった事がきっと
There must have been something...
あったんだろうな
...I wanted to tell you
恐らくありきたりなんだろうけど
It was probably something ordinary...
こんなにも
...but even so
お別れした事は
The fact that we parted...
出会った事と繋がっている
...is connected to the fact that we met
あの透明な彗星は
That transparent comet...
透明だから無くならない
...won't disappear because it is transparent
◯×△どれかなんて
Correct, wrong, or in between...
皆と比べてどうかなんて
...how do I compare to everyone else?
確かめる間も無い程
Without even the time to verify it...
生きるのは最高だ
...life is the absolute best!
あまり泣かなくなっても
Even if I don't cry much anymore
ごまかして笑っていくよ
I'll laugh it off and keep going
大丈夫だ あの痛みは
It's okay, that pain......
忘れたって消えやしない
...won't fade even if I forget it
大丈夫だ この光の
It's okay, at the beginning...
始まりには
...of this light...
君がいる
...you are there
いっせーのーせ
Ready, set, go...
で踏み込むゴールライン保存
...and cross the goal line
僕らは何も何もまだ知らぬ保存
We don't know anything, nothing at all yet
一線越えて
Once we cross the line...
振り返るともうない
...and look back, it's already gone
僕らは何も何もまだ知らぬ
We don't know anything, nothing at all yet
うだってうだってうだってく
We're burning, burning, burning up
煌めく汗がこぼれるのさ
As our glittering sweat spills over
覚えてないこともたくさんあっただろう
There were probably many things we forgot
たくさんあっただろう
There must have been many things...
誰も彼も シルエット
Everyone, every silhouette.
大事にしてたもの 忘れたフリをしたんだよ
We pretended to forget the things we cherished,
なにもないよ 笑えるさ
there's nothing, we can laugh.
いっせーのーで
In one go,
思い出す少年
remembering the boy,
僕らは
we...
何もかもを 欲しがった
...wanted everything.
わかってるって
We know,
あぁ 気づいてるって
ah, we realize,
時計の針は 日々は
the clock's hands, the days,
止まらない
won't stop.
奪って 奪って 奪ってく
Taking, taking, taking away...
流れる
...flowing...
時と
...time...
遠く 遠く 遠くになって
...getting farther and farther away.
覚えてないことも たくさんあっただろう
There must have been many things we don't remember,
誰も彼も シルエット
everyone, every silhouette.
恐れてやまぬこと 知らないフリをしたんだよ
We pretended not to know what we feared,
なにもないよ 笑えるさ
there's nothing, we can laugh.
ひらりと ひらりと 舞ってる
Fluttering and fluttering,
木の葉の様に
like the leaves,
憂うことなく 焦燥もなく
without worry or impatience,
過ごしていたいよ
I want to spend my days.
覚えてないことも たくさんあったけど
There were many things we didn't remember,
きっとずっと 変わらないものがあることを
but surely there are things that will never change.
教えてくれたあなたは
You who taught me,
消えぬ 消えぬ シルエット
are the silhouette that never fades.
大事にしたいもの 持って大人になるんだ
Holding onto the things I cherish, I'll become an adult.
どんな時も 離さずに
Never letting go, no matter when,
守り続けよう
I'll keep protecting them.
そしたら いつの日にか
Then someday,
何もかもを 笑えるさ
we can laugh at everything.
ひらりと ひらりと 舞ってる
Fluttering and fluttering,
木の葉が 飛んでゆく
the leaves are flying away.
Woah...
描いた未知のキャンバス 重ねる景色
The landscape layering on the canvas of the unknown I drew,
繋いでみて 繰り返してく衝動
try connecting them, with repeating impulses.
揺らいだ 目の前に広がる世界
The swaying world spreading before my eyes,
星屑のメロディ 歌に乗せた
I put the melody of stardust into a song.
クラっと 鮮やかに
Dazzling and vividly,
眩ませるように
as if to blind me,
駆け抜けるよ スターライト
I'll run through, Starlight!
We can fly
そう僕らは
yes, we are...
いつしか 夢の中 引かれて
...at some point drawn into the dream,
ただ がむしゃらに 走り続けたよ
just recklessly running forward.
無限の 宇宙に 響いた
Echoing in the infinite universe,
キミを 照らす 声は どこへだって きらり
the voice that shines on you, sparkling everywhere,
飛んでゆけるんだ
can fly away!
愉快な仲間と 歩いた非日常
The extraordinary days I walked with cheerful friends,
掴んでみて 指先の一等星
try grabbing it, the first-magnitude star at your fingertips.
滲んでゆく 目の前に広がった限界は
Blurring, the limits that spread before our eyes...
みんなの手 重ねて ぶっ壊して
...we'll bring them down by overlapping everyone's hands!
吸い込まれそうな
Almost being sucked in,
夜空を見上げて
looking up at the night sky,
今叫ぶよ スターライト
I'll shout now, Starlight!
I wanna be
そう僕らは
yes, we are...
いつまでも 側で 笑い合って
...always laughing together by each other's side.
あふれる声が 遠く 木霊する
Our overflowing voices echo far away,
願いの...
of our wishes...
願いのかけらを灯した
Lighting up the fragments of our wishes,
君の腕を引いて
I pull your arm...
どこへだってきらり
Anywhere, glittering,
飛んでゆけるんだ
We can fly away!
ちょっと不安な日も
Even on slightly uneasy days,
魔法をかけてハッピー
Cast a spell to make it happy,
百人力で乗り越えていこう
Let's overcome it with a hundredfold strength!
アクアブルーに染まる
Stained in aqua blue,
大空めがけた
Aiming for the great sky,
鼓動が弾んでく
Our heartbeats are racing!
We can fly そう僕らは
We can fly! Yes, we...
この日をずっと待ってたんだ
...have been waiting for this day all along.
まだ醒めないで
Please don't wake up yet,
Starlight
僕らは止まらない
We won't stop!
その光が消える
Until that light fades,
1秒前まで走り続けるよ
We'll keep running until one second before!
無限の宇宙に響いた
Echoing in the infinite universe,
キミを照らす声を
Hold tight to the voice...
強く抱いて きらり
...that shines on you, glittering...
輝いてゆけ
...and keep on shining!
いつだって愛情が先に
Love always runs ahead...
走り出す 僕らのランウェイを
...starting our runway.
頑丈とラッキーを盾に
With sturdiness and luck as our shield,
進みます ア・ユ・レディ？
We move forward. Are you ready?
転んだって 泣いたって僕ら
Even if we fall or cry, we...
慣れてるよ 受け身はパーフェクト
...are used to it; our recovery is perfect.
笑ってくれてありがとう
Thank you for smiling for me,
また僕は歌えるよ
I can sing once again!
人生は不安ばっか
Life is full of anxieties,
正直自信はないけど
And honestly, I have no confidence, but...
君の隣だけは
The space right next to you...
譲る気はないのです！
...is the one place I will never give up!
僕らが出会えた奇跡のセカイ
This miraculous world where we met,
君の目にどう映るかな
I wonder how it looks through your eyes.
青より澄み渡る
A sky clearer than blue,
僕だけの大空だといいな
I hope it's a great sky just for me.
不確かな永遠より僕は
Rather than an uncertain eternity, I......
二人で過ごす今を歌いたいんだ
...want to sing of the present we spend together.
この惑星の片隅 続く
In a corner of this planet, continuing on...
あいまいみーゆえにラブミ
It's ambiguous, so love me!
ナンセンスな現実が
A nonsensical reality...
心を乱していった
...has disordered my heart.
ラッキーの天秤の裏側にある
On the flip side of luck's scales lies...
アンラッキー
...bad luck.
転んだって 泣いたって僕ら
Even if we fall or cry, we...
立ち上がる 七転八倒さ
...will stand back up; we're resilient.
笑ってくれてありがとう
Thank you for smiling for me,
まだ僕は走れるよ
I can still run!
人生の期待感は
The expectations of life......
正直膨らむばっかでさ
...honestly just keep expanding.
君の心の中
Inside your heart......
灯る陽だまりなのです
...is a sunny spot that lights up.
僕らが暮らしてる奇跡の時代
This miraculous world where we live,
君のことどう照らすかな
I wonder how it shines upon you.
星より煌めいた
If I could become a sun......
僕らしい太陽になれたら
...shining in my own way, brighter than stars.
不確かな永遠より僕は
Rather than an uncertain eternity, I......
二人で過ごす今を楽しんでいたい
...want to enjoy the present we spend together.
この惑星の片隅 続く
In a corner of this planet, continuing on......
あいまいみーゆえにラブミ
It's ambiguous, so love me!
今日は本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you all so much for today!
ここまで活動できたのは
The reason I've been able to come this far......
応援してくれたみんなのおかげです！
...is all thanks to everyone who supported me!
いつも本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much as always!
みんな、大好きだぞー！
I love you all!
ああ健やかなる時も
Ah, in health......
ああ病める時もきっと
...and in sickness, surely......
伝えたいよこのメロディ
I want to convey this melody to you.
僕らが出会えた奇跡のセカイ
This miraculous world where we met,
君の目にどう映るかな//
I wonder how it looks through your eyes.
青より澄み渡る
A sky clearer than blue,
僕だけの大空だといいな
I hope it's a great sky just for me.
不確かな永遠より僕は
Rather than an uncertain eternity, I......
二人で過ごす今を歌いたいんだ
...want to sing of the present we spend together.
この惑星の片隅 続く
In a corner of this planet, continuing on......
あいまいみーゆえにラブミ
It's ambiguous, so love me!
アイラブユー伝えたいの
I want to tell you, 'I love you'!
これからも、楽しい事いっぱい一緒にね！
Let's keep doing lots of fun things together!!!